Translation: Cecilia HollaBella is just one Ossau Dunfield Sun
Proofreading: Mahsele Zhang XVI HollaBella
Shaft\Pressure: WILDERBEAST HollaBella Machsel Zhang
Welcome to follow Sina Weibo @马赫塞勒张 to get the video download address with embedded Chinese and English subtitles and translator annotations
The translations used in this subtitle when referring to the original text of the "Bible" are based on the "Mandarin Chinese Union Version" ("God" version)
The Psychological Significance of "Bible" Story Sixth Lecture The Flood——Psychological Background Jordan B. Peterson
Let's go directly to the topic
I also like this story
Stories about Noah's Flood and the Tower of Babel
It is as interesting as other stories in the Bible
The Tower of Babel is one of these stories
Like the story of Cain and Abel
Only a few sentences
In a way, the story of the Tower of Babel is just a fragment
Although Noah’s story is very complete
But like the stories we told before
We can analyze this story from multiple levels at the same time
So what I will do next
Start with some background knowledge
Some background knowledge of psychology
Only those knowledge stories are meaningful
The first thing I want to talk about is
You are born with a priori perception structure
This is actually a realized structure
Is human beings 3.5 billion years
The result of always trying to integrate my body
Such a long time not only changed your body
Also changed your mind
Mind is part of body
And closely attached to it
You tend to think that the brain is in your head
And it seems to be independent of the rest of the body
this is not right
You have a large and complex
The neuron system operates throughout your body
Neurons in the autonomic nervous system
More neurons than in the central nervous system
There are a lot of neurons
Your central nervous system allows you to
Exercise your ability to spontaneously control your own muscle tissue
Can also receive feedback from muscle tissue
The role of the brain is actually all over your body
What you may not know is
If you put the paraplegic patient on the treadmill to stabilize
They can actually walk
Their legs can move involuntarily controlled
Your spine can do such complex actions
Actually when you walk
It controls your feet up and down
In most cases
So what I mean by this is
Bluntly
You don’t have a sense of leaving a blank space
Understand the world as something independent of its own manifestation
This kind of consciousness does not exist
You have a built-in interpretation system
This is an unusually deep-rooted and imperceptible system
Because you will treat this system as
Hidden part of one's own subconscious
This system leads to your conscious experience
It determines what kind of person you are in the world
This is one of the ways to look at this system
This is a very good way to understand
Psychoanalysis is understood like this
This is also understood in neuroscience
Something very interesting about modern neuroscientists
Especially among the top neuroscientists and
Among the neuroscientists involved in emotion research
as far as I know
They are often obsessed with psychoanalysis
Jacques Panksepp is a good example
They agree with the claims of psychoanalysts
Think the lower subconscious and anthropomorphic motivation
Actually accurately reflects how the brain is active
So you can think of yourself as a loose collection
This collection is made up of autonomous souls
They are controlled by some primary personality
This is a reasonable way to understand
Then the problem is coming
What is the nature of the transcendental structure you used to explain the world
I think the clearest answer is "it is a story"
Because you live in the story
I think this view is very interesting
Because i think
Actually I have some videos that also illustrate this point
I think Darwin’s hypothesis
At least as basic as Newton’s hypothesis
Actually I think Darwin’s hypothesis is more basic
We have evolved a story structure
And use it to explain the world
For me
Story-based cognitive structure contains deeper truth
They are all true
At least since we developed these structures
This means we are still alive here
It took us 350 million years to develop these story structures
They are highly functional
There is no better definition of truth than highly functional
That's the best
Partly because we are limitless creatures
We can't know everything
Generally speaking, the limit we can do with knowledge
Is the function of recording things
Then improve it when it works abnormally
I think the scientific method is doing this
We gradually developed such a story structure
And use it to explain the world
This thing is so interesting
What it describes is the basic essence of the story
However, it is also strange that
We have knowledge of the known and the unknown
Clear division of labor in the left and right hemispheres
Or the cognition of chaos and order
Sorry to say that order and chaos will be treated separately
This also reveals some basic nature of the world
If you assume that we have evolved to
Can reflect the structure of the world
Generally speaking
Obviously this is not just a physical structure
Matter particles like atoms and molecules
It’s formed by matter particles over time
The increasingly complex structure and all its performance modes
This includes human interaction
Political interaction
Economic interaction
Interactions in the family
These are important parts of our reality
But maybe in a sense
They are not what physicists are concerned about
Something as basic as physical properties
We live in the story
I want to say more about the story and its structure
When you understand a little bit of the structure of the story
Then this whole set of myths
Suddenly everything makes sense
This is very useful
What you can see is
Many daily events in everyone’s life
Are generally described in mythology
This helped us a lot
First of all it makes you no longer isolated from the world
I realized one thing while studying clinical psychology
This is contrary to the view of antipsychiatrists
That is, diagnosis is often a relief for the visitor
There was a problem when the patient was diagnosed
Because you might be labeled
And this label may follow you for life
Once you have been tagged
A lot of strange things happen around you
These things usually reinforce that label
Maybe you will show it more through action
Or you will internalize it as your own identity
There is another situation
This is what you said in the mouth of a doctor or a psychologist
The last words to hear
It’s "I’ve never seen a situation like you."
Yes
This is not a relief
If the doctor gave you the information
"I have never heard of anything similar to what you are talking about."
The result of saying this may be of little benefit to you
Or you don’t want to listen anymore
Because in their eyes you are a disturbing vision
In the eyes of these people with professional medical knowledge, you are a monster
But you are still trying to ask them for advice
It is true
As long as you can be classified into one category
The doctor will know how to treat you
This is actually a relief for the doctor
It's the same for you, right
Think about it when you go to the doctor and say
"Oh, I can't get out of the house anymore"
"I'm afraid of taking the elevator."
"I get heart palpitations when I take the elevator."
"Sometimes I was sent to the emergency room."
"My range of activities in life is constantly restricted"
"I can only stay at home"
"I am afraid that I will die of a heart attack."
The psychologist will say
"You have a fear of heights"
"Many people have a fear of heights."
"This is how it usually comes out"
"These are treatment options."
"We have some ways to treat it."
"You should not die from a heart attack for the time being"
Then this is a relief
"You are not crazy like no other in the world."
"You still have medicine to save"
This is a huge relief
People take a brood of worried snakes to the doctor
And when they left there was only one snake left to handle
Although it is still a snake
But the handleable snake is much better than the Hydra
Back to the story itself
The stories we tell and the stories we live in
Is our basic way of dealing with the complexity of the world
in my opinion
Basic problems of the world
It's not only that it's too complicated to understand
And this complexity will become unpredictable
This is actually a Darwinian dilemma
This is why Darwinism looks
There is a practical necessity on the issue of continuing life
Complexity is always changing in unpredictable ways
And you may not be able to figure it out
What will work in the future
According to the Darwinian solution process is this
First produce almost random variants
And then make any one of them can accidentally
Happens to survive in the environment
To be precise it is not random
Because the hidden structure has always been conserved
The child is born with an extra arm or something similar
Are rare
The bone structure of your body in the history of evolution
Can be traced back to animals long ago
There are many things that have been conserved during evolution
There are some changes within the conservative, just like music
Music is a good example of understanding this change
The stories we tell have exactly the same structure
They have their own core elements and their own changes
Okay let's go back to those stories
I just mentioned the first question
It's about complexity
Things are often too complicated to handle
This often leads to serious consequences
Everyone ends up like this
Their lives have become too complicated
To the point of death
A lot will happen as you go to death
Terrible things related to complexity
You may get serious illness that you can't handle
Or walk in in an intimate relationship
A dead end with no way out
This happens too often to people
For example, those who want to commit suicide
I often feel that they are driven to desperation
There is no correct option
Face terrible things no matter where you turn
And they don’t see any way out
Sometimes this is more real than you think
We tend to think
The problems of these people are mainly psychological problems
But actually not
As a clinician, you will soon realize one thing
I.e. people come to you
Because they have mental illness
It’s because of problems in dealing with complexity
Their lives are out of their control
They don’t know how to regain control of their lives
Many things will make you fall into this trouble
Then of course it will make you anxious or depressed
This is the fuse of almost all mental illnesses
But the basic question is still
Things are beyond your ability
This is actually a physiological and psychological problem
Not a purely psychological problem
Your abilities have an upper limit
From a resource point of view
Your ability is not enough to solve the urgent complexity
Your ability is not enough
If you get into an overly complicated situation
You will exhaust your physical and psychological resources
This is what the concept of chaos represents
It represents the complexity below the surface
Can surface all the time
It will surface in this case as an example
When you wake up and feel a little pain in some parts of your body
"It should be okay" you ignore it
But it got worse and you ended up in the hospital
Maybe you will find an analogy
You have pancreatic cancer
You can only live for another six months
It's over
At this time you finally stepped through the thin ice that everyone walked on
You now know what's under the surface
Beneath the surface is the deep-rooted complexity of life
This is chaos
People have spent a long time
To understand this conceptual "schema"
Before human beings have a clear understanding of it
Basically rely on imagination and story to complete this understanding
There are some images that represent the hidden chaos
One of them is the Chaos Dragon
It's exactly like the picture just now
The dragons that heroes have to face
Is a symbol of the unknown
Is something lurking under the surface
Dragons often guard the treasure
Because the unknown contains possibilities
We mentioned before
In the creation myth of Mesopotamia
Water exists at the beginning of time
Including salt water and clear water
Are all symbols of chaos before the universe formed
For example, people often dream
I guess many of you have had this dream
Dreaming that I am in a house I am familiar with
But suddenly found one or several new rooms
Maybe some new rooms were found in the basement
These rooms are often messy
There is water everywhere
These are very common things
It means you broke
The limits of your conscious self-understanding
Go to a new field full of possibilities
But this new field has an amazing amount of work to be done
Think this is a whole new part of you
But it has not been well developed
Essentially it is filled with chaos
I think the reason
Partly because chaos is not only when you didn’t expect it
Where the fall
And you are directly facing
And the unknown from which new things are born
Water is a symbol of life especially in the desert
Because life cannot do without water
When you want to talk about something that can both give life
And potentially fatal things
Water naturally becomes their symbol
A little water can quench thirst
But a lot of water can cause a shipwreck
These are the two extremes of water
There are many such subtexts in "Genesis"
There are also other places in the Old Testament
About God conquered a powerful monster
Leviathan or Behemoth
It has a snake-like appearance
The result of this conflict is that the world was created
This is a concept about the power of creation
Which is the logos we talked about earlier
It is constantly facing chaos
Another way to look at chaos is
Think of it as an aggressive creeping monster
They often live in the abyss or underwater
I think this may be due to
We are using our own predator detection circuit
To complete this pre-cognitive process
Its basic point is
Your predator detection circuit is used
Deal with instant threats
It is fast but the resolution is low
It doesn't contain much thinking
But it's really fast
This also illustrates our ability and tendency
That quickly move those
The people who subvert our conceptual structure
Seen as an enemy of a predator variant
We will react this way without thinking
This is the prototype
If something rushes over and scares you
For example, a shark
Is something lurking underwater
It will pull you to the bottom
Then it's your enemy
Then you should be prepared
This is a very reasonable defense strategy
Although it is also risky
And sometimes errors
The picture we use to build the story
Basically an all-encompassing chaos
This chaos is beyond our ability to understand
On all levels
Individual level, family level, social level, economic level
We are all constantly being
The threat posed by the collapse of the environment where one lives
For example, you have a house
How much time did you spend maintaining it
Of course it took a lot of work, why did you do this?
Because the house will collapse on its own because of your stupidity
You didn't maintain it properly causing it to fall apart
Or you overlooked something, right
I say these for some professional reasons
The house collapsed because of your incompetence
But even if you have the ability it will still collapse
This is the principle of entropy
Things have a tendency to fall apart on their own
So you have to do your best
To keep things as they are
Of course
It will turn a blind eye to you
Bad repair skills
And your unwillingness to become complicated
We will return to a very classic point of view
A point made by Mircea Iliad
He is a famous religious historian
He extracted this point of view from the massive flood legends
There are two reasons why the earth will periodically have disasters
One is because things decompose themselves
Is the principle of entropy increase
I don’t remember which law of thermodynamics is
But a very important law in thermodynamics
Is one of the three laws of thermodynamics
Things fall apart spontaneously
This is one of the things we have to fight against
2. The speed of things collapse will be accelerated by human sin
Everyone knows this truth
You know very well in your heart
For example, your car broke down on the highway
You will think it is really inconvenient
You punched the sky
But at the same time another part of you
Will mutter deep in your heart
"I know the car keeps clicking but I ignore it
"And it actually foreshadows something."
"I know I should pay more attention to this."
"But I didn't, so I got into where I am now"
I bet these things happen two or three times a week
People do something they know they shouldn’t do
And told myself not to do stupid things a few seconds ago
A voice in their hearts said
"Don't do that" "I know, I know"
But you knowingly committed
Seek benevolence
Self-inflicted
Then you suffered a double injury
Because not only did things fall apart
And you're the fool who let it fall
I knew it would collapse but I ignored it
This is the concept behind this view
Things fall apart for two reasons
Thermodynamic entropy increase and
People have such a tendency
Ignore some things I know I should do
We did this partly because
When problems arise
I will always announce my arrival
Unless it's so small that you can automatically solve it
Its appearance is always accompanied by negative emotions
This is part of the predator detection circuit
It will fail, disappointment, grief
Or to announce its arrival in the worst form of anxiety
Not surprising because it is a problem, right
One of the logical responses is
Be dazed by the problem
But as long as it is a problem, it can be classified and solved
Staying and running away is not a good solution
Because things tend to fall apart autonomously
If you just throw it aside
It will only get worse, not better
This is a very disturbing thing in life
for example
If you have received a warning from the tax bureau
You ignored it
The probability of it disappearing is almost zero, right?
What will actually happen
The more you ignore the problem, the more serious it becomes
If you ignore it long enough
It becomes powerful enough to swallow you
Then you're done
I was reading "Harpers Magazine" once
It says people would rather be robbed than be charged
I believe this is true
Because the robbery is over
Only a few minutes of pure horror
Lost your wallet and life as usual
And auditing is like a semi-fatal disease
This is chaos
Here is a point about chaos
The psychological point of view
Chaos is actually
The spirit of God depicted in Genesis
Something orderly extracted at the beginning of time
This is what we are constantly fighting against
We also fight to construct in the same way
And maintain the world we live in
This is amazing
In an environment called "pre-cosmic chaos" by Eliad
Our ancestors were surrounded by predators
And the way our neural structure is built
Was born to deal with this environment
When I first connected the two
Really initiating
It speaks for itself
The world is too complicated for us to handle
This is one of the problems we have to continue to face
Then the question is how do you deal with it
Things will get worse if you ignore it
So ignoring it is no use at all
We know this
So if you ignore it, it's useless
Then do something it might be useful
For example, I found in Egyptian mythology
Horus is the god of attention
There is such a god in Mesopotamian mythology
Marduk has a ring of eyes above his head
How can we turn the tide before the building will fall
The answer to this is to take the initiative to deal with them
This fits well with those hero myths
These myths all preach a point of view
If there is a dragon hiding around you
Hiding it in the basement will only make it stronger
It's time to go out and face those problems
The usual story is
You might be killed by a dragon
After all, it's a dragon
But this is only a possibility
The opposite is undoubtedly
If you happen to be attacked at home in the middle of the night
You still have a hangover
It just ended a bad day
At this time you are not ready for your sword and shield
Usually this is what happens in those
The situation in the person who is running away
This is not something we should promote
How you choose is a dead end
It's good to be extremely pessimistic at a certain point
That’s it’s so liberating
It's a relief to happen often
This is really a habit worth developing
Sometimes you get stuck no matter what you do
Being an extremely pessimist is a relief
So you won't struggle everywhere to find a way out
Because there is no way out
You can choose the tragic way of death A
I know it sucks to look at things this way
But it is very helpful for understanding the following question
That is, many times you always have the least of two evils
If this is all you can do
If life is like this for you
Okay, come on
Make the worst choice
Also the best thing you can do
Good enough
Especially with another option
The worst option is even more so
anyway
The basic reality of things is complex beyond understanding
The question is how do you face it
Here is the part of the patriarchal order
I have to declare in advance
The "patriarchy" here is analyzed from a positive perspective
After the patriarchal structure is missing
Can't think of a better word right now
The rest can only be chaos
Chaos is not a good thing
If it's too messy
The less self you can keep
If you think you can have no prior structure
And the context of the social structure
Then you really know too little about humans
Because for one thing I observed, for example
Our ability to maintain our sanity depends largely on
A well-ordered social structure
The reason is this
First of all you have to know what you do almost every day
You have to have a fixed daily routine
Because humans are also animals
If you have a dog or cat, you know
Dog is a good example
Dogs like a fixed daily routine
They like a fixed number of times per day
Go for a walk at a fixed time
If you don’t regulate their daily routine
They will get sick soon
The same for children
It can be exaggerated but in general
You still have to know the approximate time to wake up
About the same time every day
You have to know your approximate food
Need to know what to eat
With whom
You have to know where to buy ingredients
70% to 80% of your life
It's almost this ratio
Are made up of the procedures you repeat every day
But these repeated parts are often considered by many people to be
The least important part of their lives
But one thing I must point out is
You will know
I have analyzed this to a client of mine
He suffered a lot of crimes for coaxing his children to sleep
It's a battle every night
Research at that time has shown
Most parents spend only 20 minutes a day on average
Be alone with your children
Because everyone is too busy
Set aside 20 minutes of one-on-one time every day
It's actually not that easy
These 20 minutes are much longer than you think
But it’s only 20 minutes
My client spends about 40 minutes a day
Bother trying to put the child to bed
It's not fun at all
You might think okay
It's just a little trouble making the kids sleep
Things are not as simple as you think
If this kind of petty fight is performed every day
It was a disaster
So do the math for yourself
Just roughly assume 5 hours a week
Don't need to be too precise
That is 20 hours a month
240 hours per year
Count it down to six 40-hour work weeks
In other words, he wasted a month and a half of the work week
I can't do anything, I can only fight against my son
Just to put my son to bed
Sounds terrible right
If you want to have a positive relationship with others
It’s best not to spend too much time on this kind of thing
This is too bad
Therefore you need a structure
Need for predictability
You need them more than you think
To help you stay sane
If you are lucky
May sound weird
You can deviate from normal behavior patterns by 5%
Or 10% more
But also with caution and caution
As long as you haven’t deviated from the usual
Then it's OK to be a little abnormal
Maybe it can be maintained for a long time
The people around you can also tolerate your aberrations
Or maybe you are really lucky
You are very creative, decent and organized
People will be more than happy to contact you
Because you are so unique
But even in this case
In general, what you need most is a fixed schedule
An orderly and predictable schedule
Then be able to strictly enforce it
In this way you will be healthier, happier and more rational
There is one more thing you need
I think the psychoanalyst here is wrong
They overestimate the internal rational construction
Importance to sound mind
Because from a psychological point of view
You are "self" in a way
It's inside you
Of course it lives on the unconscious structure
The purpose of psychoanalysis is to clarify this unconscious structure
And the self attached to it
To help you become a completely independent individual
But this perception has a problem
Because you as a rational and autonomous human
Not all because your mind is organized
Although it is important
If your subconscious and self-organized
Why you can stay sane
Because the people around you can
Tolerate your various behaviors
And whenever you act too stupidly
They will alert you in time
If you don’t realize it, you will get people’s permanent disgust
People do it all the time
I can't get tired of it
Send this kind of spiritual message back and forth
For example, if people behave reasonably
And you are happy to see it happen, you will smile at them
Otherwise you will frown
Or ignore them
Avoid them and roll their eyes at them
You make an expression of disgust and don't listen to them
You interrupt them not to cooperate with them
Disdain to compete
You frequently send this kind of signal to others
To regulate their behavior
All your social interactions are doing things like this
This is why we communicate face to face
And why our faces express emotions
We look at each other
Can know each other's current status
Because we can’t directly understand what each other is thinking
In part, you do a fixed schedule
To mold yourself into such a
A trustworthy and perhaps funny person
At the same time, he won’t do anything too out of line
Everyone around you
Are shaping you in this way
Make sure you look the way you should
This is why you stay sane
If people don’t have a fixed schedule
They will start to become isolated and erratic
Deviated further and further
Because the world is too complicated
It is impossible to keep its organization organized by oneself
You really can't do it
So we use other means to stay sane
This is very wise
Because the spiritual and mental issues are too complicated
The way we deal with this complexity is
We have developed an extremely large brain capacity
We use it to handle many problems in parallel
It can be said to be like a "mental stock market"
I use this term deliberately
Because the stock market is also doing the impossible
It tries to price things
But it can't be done
There are countless items in the world
How can you price each item?
Can't do it at all
That’s why the stock market came into being
From the consumer point of view that is the free market
So in the free market
Everyone is voting all the time to determine the price of everything
We price items in this way
Because it’s impossible to price each item individually
This is part of the reason why the stock market soars from time to time
And things like stock market bubbles
Having said that, what I mean by this is
Everything is chaotic
In "Alice in Wonderland"
Alice fell into the rabbit hole
The underground world
Since then she has been exposed to the underlying structure of being
She met the red queen
Mother Nature
Mother Nature is running around
Clamoring to cut off someone's head
This is exactly what Mother Nature is doing
She told Alice
"In my kingdom you have to run as hard as you can
"Can stay in place"
The fact is
Evolutionary biologists and psychologists
Put forward the so-called "red queen hypothesis"
The content of this hypothesis is
You are facing all kinds of situations all the time
And your intelligence is not enough to face or face everything
This is an eternal problem
So how do you face it
You rely on your own biological structure
Your physical avatar can partially solve this problem
Besides, you can be shaped by the environment
Therefore
You learned a lot of things you need to know
But the most important thing is that you learned
How to communicate effectively with others in a good manner
Once you have the ability to do so
You can always use external forces to solve problems
This is also what you do everyday
Our daily interaction is to continuously communicate solutions
If you are a social person
This is what you need to do
If you plan to have children
There is something to understand
I seem to have mentioned in a previous lecture
As a parent of extremely young children
Your goal is before the child is four years old
Nurture them to be extremely popular with the environment
If you can achieve this goal
They have successfully finalized
Because everyone is happy to have their company
Once people want to interact with them
I want to play with them
Want to cooperate with
Have the desire to compete
It's as if all the doors are open for them
The reason why they can stay sane
Because everyone loves and is willing to help them
So your goal is to do as much as possible
Make them acceptable and welcome in the social environment
It’s not that we should turn them into soulless walking dead
That is a tyrant-style compulsory socialization
For example, the common reprimand "Don't do anything wrong"
This is not a good way
Although this is a good suggestion in itself
But this advice is not complete
You have to do a lot of things right
So that people like to have your company
Encourage what you do
This is you as a parent
Things to do besides instilling normative awareness
This schematic is like this
The Father is followed by a round of sun
He rules this walled city
He can be said to be the soul of this city
This picture is really wonderful
The same can be said
He is the collective spirit of this city
In other words, the collective spirit of the city has accumulated over time
Or the collective spirit of strength
This force has built and maintained the city over time
This statement is better
Here is connected with the sun again
Because the sun symbolizes enlightenment and light
And everything related to higher consciousness and revelation
This is a very subtle picture
Then on this basis, I give this explanation
Of course patriarchy may develop into autocracy
This does happen often
This is a persistent danger in human civilization
Civilization is the antidote to chaos
But it will develop out of control from time to time
I became a problem of myself
Roughly speaking, it looks like a super problem
It will create chaotic problems
Each solution creates certain problems
No one solution is perfect
You have to find balance
For postmodernists
One thing can be said that annoys me
They keep complaining about patriarchy
It's really annoying
The social structure is autocratic, which speaks for itself
What's the fuss about this, friends
This couldn't be more obvious
But the social structure is not exactly like this
Patriarchy can be said to be a one-dimensional problem
Extremely simplified solution
Some people think this is dictatorship
Actually not at all
If you stay in a place where only dictatorship remains in the first half of the year
You will soon find the difference
But this does not mean
Even if you live in a free and enlightened Western society
People don’t need to make any sacrifices to participate in social construction
We are all shaped by the autocratic side of social customs
But basically
This is more pros than cons
Furthermore, do you have to sacrifice too much for the group?
The choice is yours
If you make too much sacrifice for the group
You will be aware
Because you will start to be angry and irritable to others
Your mental mechanism is telling you this in this way
It depends on whether you want to fight
The huge pressure of complying with social regulations
To keep your individual logos
This is the problem you have to face
The collective wants you to behave
If you can follow the norms and be creative
That would be better
But this situation is very rare
Generally speaking, the group just wants you to behave well
This is the authoritarian part
Is there any other alternative
Our society is built on consensus
Consensus is based on a certain degree of individual sacrifice
Although the individual is a social revival
An absolutely necessary revitalizing force
It is difficult to grasp this problem
Anyway your physical structure
Is your first line of defense against chaos
Your body presents you to the world in a certain way
The second line of defense can be said to be
The social structure you live in
You can also call it the ability hierarchy
Thank goodness
Maybe you can master one or two things in your life
But you have to know a little bit more about it
If you face all possible situations alone
You are solving difficult math problems
Watching the bathtub leak all over the place but feel helpless
This is not so good
You can call a plumber at this time
Everything is fine
We tend to cooperate with each other to control the chaos
At the same time, it also controls the orderly development
Political dialogue is like this, right
We maintain culture to control chaos
At the same time find a balance in it to control the rational development of culture
Only in this way can we
In a peaceful and productive way
Life for a long time
The best we can do
We should be grateful when things work effectively
Because everything is in the natural state
Not only do they not work well on their own
Will gradually get worse over time
You should be amazed whenever anything is working properly
So what does this framework look like?
I think it should be like this
In my opinion, it is the basic structure of many things
It is a basic structured story
Is the basic conceptual framework
In Heidegger's words, the basic Dasein
It is the frame of the world in which you live
You must exist in one
No exception
You can convert between different frames
But the essence remains the same, you are still in the frame
This is the world you live in
You exist somewhere
It is inevitable
Although you may not know where you live
It means you are in chaos
In this case, you have to look back carefully
Figure out where you are now
It's like you're lost
The problem with it is
You don't know where to go
Because you have countless places to go
The problem is that there are too many options
There are too many places where you can stay safe and sound
It's not a good thing to be lost
You have to know where you are
I built an online project with my partner
Called "Past Writing Project"
This project helps people clarify their past
It breaks down life into six stages
We call each stage a period
Then find out the deepest moments in each period
Record what happened
Good or bad
What is the corresponding result at the same time
What did you get from it
Maybe you could have chosen another way of doing things
Maybe you can learn something from it
In this way you can clear the fog
Find a direction for yourself
But many people don’t like to do this
Because they actually don’t want to know
They would rather be muddled
Open one eye to everything, close one eye
Fancy that the surrounding environment is much better than the actual situation
Trying to deceive myself in an ambiguous state
They would rather do this than face actual problems
But you better go face them up
Because once you have a clear problem
You clarify the problems and understand their essence
You can start to solve the problem
Step by step
But if you don’t know where you live
There is no way to talk about it
You will be aware of this state
It's easy to feel
If you have been entangled in the past by things in your dreams
It may have been more than a year
But you are still troubled by it every now and then
They appear repeatedly in your dreams
Means you have not extracted that world from past experience
Your potential is still trapped in the past
To face it is to face the dragon of the past
Of course it is scary
Sometimes things can be really scary
For example, you may be at a loss and confused
The reason is that you suffered severe abuse in your childhood
For example, when I was four years old
The abuser may be a family member
Because family members are often the abuser
And this will only make things worse
this means
You have encountered a deliberate evil
If you say it wrong, you have directly encountered deliberate evil
But tortured you for a long time
Is the hypothesis implicit in this malice
It's stuck in your memory lingering
Imprisoned in the representational structure
As an adult you have to fully express it
Then it is possible to get relief from it
This is not a joke
In many cases people need to go back to the past
This is the job of a psychoanalyst
People have to look back in the past to discover old things
Aware of the serious blow they bring to themselves
It’s not that people deliberately suppressed these memories
We will not discuss some of Freud's fallacies for now
He's a genius, so let's not talk about it
Sometimes it’s not suppressed
It’s because people were young when these bad things happened
They simply cannot have this ability
To figure out what happened and how to deal with it
Or what is the meaning of these things
Then you can coexist with it
When you do
It’s as if your body is in contact with the world in stages
And it develops very fast
It may take years of development
But the initial stage of development is very rapid
Like you are walking on the street
Suddenly there was a loud noise behind me
You will make this defensive action
By the way, this is the predator defense response
You will squat like this
This posture is to prevent the other person from jumping on your back
So as to easily attack your neck
About a few hundred milliseconds of response time
The process is very fast and may be shorter than this
It's best to do so, otherwise it might be a snake
Can easily kill you
So you better respond quickly
But even this kind of efficiency is not high
It can deal with dangerous snakes at best
Or the swiftness of predatory cats
It will be the fastest
Then you can analyze and classify these experiences, which takes time
You are at the emotional level first
Then deal with them on a cognitive level
You can think about it
Maybe you meet at work
Especially maliciously aggressive
People often meet this kind of person
Like a bully
It's useless to do bad things all day long
And only spend the rest of my life in this state
Faced with this situation you are at a loss
You will be in "prey" mode
I’m not referring to the “prayer” pattern
Although it's kind of useful
I mean you will act like a predator
You have the following extremely complex issues to analyze
"What's wrong with this person?"
"Why make my life so bad"
"Is this treatment caused by me?"
It is not so easy to solve these mysteries
You are easily trapped inside and can't get out
Maybe you just can't do it
It may be for you to develop a clear view of good and evil
To face all the malice around me
And this kind of ability happens to be something you don't have
It's that simple
This is especially true for children
Even many adults can’t do it
To solve these problems is not so simple
Generally these are suffering from
What soldiers with post-traumatic stress disorder have to face
Because of some terrible things they have experienced
Or something that you made or witnessed
They need to update their moral model of the world
Otherwise they will end up in a hell-like situation
So you have to know where you are
Is what this picture shows
Where do you live
You are always adjusting your course of action
Like a sailor on the boundless ocean
That's why you are a mobile creature
You are always on the way to a certain destination
Not like some kind of brainless marine life
Fix yourself on the rock motionless
There is a small animal called Hydra which is quite interesting
Simple structure and compact size
The juvenile hydra has a brain because it needs to swim around
Until the Hydra reaches adulthood
It will attach to the rock and start digesting its own brain
If you just sit still on the rock
Of course you don’t need a brain
But we are not like this
We explore this world everywhere
We are navigators
There are two things you need to know to navigate for yourself
First, know where you are
You must know this precisely and clearly
You have to know your strengths and weaknesses
From your personal point of view
You can refer to others’ opinions
But this is a problem you have to solve on your own
For example, when I assess the status quo, I say "as far as I am concerned"
"What advantages do I have and which areas need improvement"
At this time, you should also be careful not to criticize yourself too much
Because this behavior is actually a disadvantage
The next question is where are you going
What is your goal
This is the so-called frame
You can think deeply about this before you tackle it
You need to think clearly about the following questions
What kind of person are you
What is your goal and the reason for it
How do you achieve your goal
Few people think about these issues
As an educator, this really surprised me
I applied another project to my class
This is one of my project package series
Called "Future Writing Project"
This was developed when I opened the "Map of Meaning" series of courses
Some materials in my lectures are also derived from this
In class I asked students to write down their past
Are we talking about stories?
Why not tell your story
Who are you how did you get here what is your state now
This will help people calm down some of the problems in their lives
Although you will face a lot of pressure when implementing this method
The pressure goes up straight when you do it
You may be malaise for weeks
Then the pressure gradually eased and remained at a low level
This is why people usually don’t do this
After all, no one likes to put pressure on themselves
But if the pressure is only temporary, it's just a sacrifice
I just said the next question is where will you go
There is something I can’t understand
Students who have received almost 14 years of education
Most of them are top students
They live so old
No one has ever asked them to sit down seriously for a day to answer a question
"Okay, please come to prove the meaning of your existence."
Tell the truth, you are in college
Taking a lot of classes
Made a vague business plan
Can you defend your meaning in life?
After all, this is what you want to achieve
Success or failure in one fell swoop
Ask yourself what your plan is
How can you be sure of your so-called life plan
It was not brainwashed by a boastful arrogant
If you haven’t considered this issue seriously
That's probably brainwashed
It’s best to think about whether you want to realize your so-called dream
Jung said such a sentence
"You live in a story whether you know it or not."
He made the following two great comments on this
"If you live in other people’s stories,
"It's very likely that you're just a perpetrator
"It's not necessarily the role you want."
"Or maybe you are unaware of the story you are acting in
"Then it is very likely that this story has a very negative ending"
"Or it's a totally bad story"
If you don’t know what the story you are acting in is like
That’s probably what I just described
Maybe you live in a story led by your mother
Or your grandmother’s female elder
God knows where you learned it from
You are always affected by the surrounding environment and personnel
Humans are like this
Maybe you are unconsciously acting in a malicious tragedy
There is something you better ask yourself
How miserable is your life?
Better to add the word futile
Ask yourself how miserable and useless your life is
You might say, uh, about 70% each
Then you are probably acting in a tragedy accidentally
Maybe this is not the best explanation
Otherwise, the whole world hates you
At least seven adults hate you
Anyway in this project
We asked the students to write down some details
Not about what they are after
This is not a business plan or something
This is the closest thing most people come up with
They have their own business plan
No, this is not just a matter of career planning
Career planning is important, yes but only secondary
For example, you have three years now
You have to live it anyway
Use these three years to create the environment around you
So that you can live as comfortable as possible
It's as if you are really taking care of yourself
What would everything be like if you did this
For convenience, let’s assume that
If you know where you are
Then you can find what is most beneficial to you
What would it be
I guess you never asked yourself this question
Because people ignore this problem
All kinds of problems in life are like sneaking snakes
Waiting to give them a head-on blow
And many people just avoid the problem
As the years go by
People find that things are not developing as they thought
A large part of the reason is
People don't know where they are
Because they don't care about this
Or I don’t know that this is a problem that needs attention
That is ignorance and turning a blind eye, right
Two catastrophic causes
People never figure out their destination and why they want to go
There is a problem in finding a destination
It means that you must be clear in your heart what definition of failure is
People usually don't like it
But if you've been so confused
You will be unaware that you have failed
This is not so good because you just keep frustrating like this
But I'm blinded to it
Although this way you can avoid a lot of suffering in the short term
But if you are clear about your definition of success
You will be soberly aware of your failures every time
This is a good thing so you have the opportunity to fix it
You can correct your defects in your behavior
Or some of your cognitive deficiencies in the situation
Or adjust your plan in time
It's not too late anyway
Good you are in this frame
In my opinion you have to make it become
A best life plan
Because you have no choice
If you don't
Or not consciously
As psychoanalysts pointed out
You are composed of countless quasi-autonomous subsystems
They can write stories improvised
And you are just practicing these stories
You know it well
Because if you observe yourself for more than two weeks
You will miss my goodness
How many stupid things I did in these two weeks
Then you will think why
That's because you are a random
Quasi-autonomous personality unit
Not one dominant
They activate whenever they want
At first you were hungry and then you were thirsty again
Then you want to sleep with your wife
Then you want to sleep in
You want to scold your boss
You still want to curse the guy who drove you on the road
You are like a two year old
Emotional patterns emerge one after another
They compete with each other for dominance
There is no top-down hierarchy
There is no king at the top
We have discussed the capability pyramid
The most advanced ability is
An ability to integrate all of these together
This is explained in the field of neurology
I will explain to you later
In a sense how are these
Mapped to the neural structure of your being
You want to control something
You want to control
It should be the ability to pay attention and learn, right
Everything else in the hierarchy must give way
Your attention and learning ability
You can think
This is the meaning of logos
There is no doubt about this
Because in the logos
Part is attention and part is communication
You can learn a lot from communicating with other people
You need to know where you are
It’s like your own GPS
It is the closest we have
Smart control system stuff
Such as your car GPS device
These things are very smart
They know where you are and where to go
Of course if you deviate from the route
They will recalculate your route
These things are almost alive
They are too close to smart
You can see this because they are acting in a smart way
They constantly solve problems
By the way, this is a cybernetic model
Cybernetic model is the basic model of GPS system
This is not accidental
You need to know where you are
You need to know where you are going
The next thing you need to know is
How will you act how to move your body
Drive yourself in time and space
From one end to the other
Next we can come to something more complicated
Because this is too simple
We do
So to be precise you don’t live in such a
But you live in these levels of nesting
You can think of this as your own internal patriarchy
This is a good way of thinking
It might be a tyrant
It may also be something that can give you
Security and autonomous functions
Maybe this is what you are looking for
But this is a battle, know it
There is something authoritarian in everyone's heart
So in the highest level of analysis
This will be the most important story
Maybe you think "I want to be a good person"
"Or I want to become famous"
I think "good" may be preferable
Because you can define "good" whatever you want
As long as it is not too disgusting
Otherwise they will only hinder you
It's no good
So you have to negotiate with people
Suppose you are a good person
This is a story at the highest level
Then you can break it down into
Your main roles
Maybe you are a good parent
Maybe you are a good employer
Maybe you are a good employee
Maybe you are a good brother
Maybe you are a good boy
These are the main roles you play in life
So you would say a good person
Is the common trait of the strengths of all your roles
Is a high-level abstraction extracted from more similar things
Take the role of "good parents"
"What are the elements that make up a good parent?"
You might say "a good parent"
Obviously this is not meant to be deadly
"Good parents need to have a good job and be able to take care of their families"
Then you might say
"What does it mean to take good care of my family?"
Then you will say
"That means you can cook something unusual."
I hope it's not too unusual
"You can cook something unusual."
"It also means you can play with your baby."
Then you will say
"Then how to play with the baby?"
"Play peekaboo or tickling with your baby"
Here is a cool conversion
Because these can be clarified and conceptualized, right
Up to this level
Then suddenly came to your body
Because how would you play peekaboo with your baby
You won’t discuss with him how you play peekaboo, do you
You will be like this it's funny
You can even play this game with seniors
They will even be amused, right
"Dad is gone" The baby is terrified
"Where did he go? Look at him again."
The baby is playing with the reliability of this world
So this is really an intense game for babies
Like this, "oh no dad is gone"
"Oh look, he shows up again"
"Oh no, he disappeared again"
And Dad’s smile shows those brief disappearances
It's not that there is fear beyond the processing power
The key is if you play peekaboo with a baby
You won't think about anything anymore
This is not in the realm of expression or abstraction
But what you actually do with your body
So for me it is a good
Multi-stage methods to solve mental and physical problems
Because the fact is
Higher levels of abstraction are clear and conceptual
But if you fully decompose it
Will become actual behavior
These behaviors involve movement of the muscular system
This is not a conceptual thing
The great thing about this hierarchical order is that
It contains educational significance
If you want to teach others or even teach yourself something
One thing you need to do is
You have to give the highest resolution possible
A detailed description of this need to be performed
I will give you a concise example
I may repeat this but it's okay
For example, you have a three-year-old child
Their house is a mess
Monsters will come out from under their bed at any time
Unless there is some order in the room
You tell your child "clean up the messy house"
You left and come back
The children still look like throwing Lego bricks everywhere
They didn't clean up at all
You think that is a bad boy
Then this is a bad inference
Because you point directly from the highest point to the bottom
If you want to fight with the people and destroy them
Then you have to do this
You don’t even think about the details
Just stabbed to the point and said "You are a bad boy, stupid boy"
"And you've always been so rotten wood that cannot be carved"
"I can't teach you anything"
This way you can lock in with the same humiliation
His past, present and future
"You have always been such a bad person"
"There is nothing to teach you."
"And your future will always be like this."
If you treat them like this, they will only be left to beat you
Because it's like this, you won't be able to recover
You have completely restricted them
So if you want a quarrel that is meaningless
You just say "past now and future"
"You are not a good person"
Destroy their conceptual structure
Let them be completely exposed to the chaos
Very good you won a big quarrel
But this is not a good thing for your long-term partner
Unless you want them to be scared to death
The attitude towards you has also been shaped into
Extreme and endless resentment
In this example, it will not affect your emotional life
How much benefit
So for a three-year-old child, what you might want to do is
Choose the level of analysis they can actually operate
If you pay attention to a child
This is all you can do
Many adults will not pay attention to children
Because they are afraid of children
They are afraid that they will make mistakes with their children
Or afraid that children don’t like them
Or something else
What you need to do to make your child like you
Spend two seconds following him
He will like you immediately
Attention is the ultimate wealth of children
They need adult attention
Because adults know so much more than them
They like to be followed
All you have to do is follow them
They will like you immediately
So you have to tell the child
"Have you seen a teddy bear?"
The children said "I saw it"
Then you are sure that the child has
Mastered the art of perceiving teddy bears
They will say "yes"
This is a complicated thing, friends
A six-month-old child can’t do it
A three-year-old child has already put the whole teddy bear
The recognition subroutine is automated
"Teddy Bear" "Yes"
"Can you pick it up" "Yes"
Touch your head "good job"
"Did you see the hole in the shelf?" "I saw it?"
"Can you put the teddy bear on the shelf?" "Yes."
"Let it go" Touch your head "It's great"
OK "Now we do the second thing and the third thing"
You are building a whole set from the bottom up
Micro routine procedures for cleaning the room
You construct these into their bodies
Because you start with what they have automated
Constructed to the level of abstraction
So once the child has all the micro routine procedures
How many microprograms are there to clean the room 200?
Many but not unlimited
So you teach them all the microprograms
Then you can say "Run a set of microprograms"
This means cleaning your room
Then they can do
They know what it means
But you have to build from the bottom up
Many times when you are arguing with someone
This person lives with you
Suppose you love this person too
Although these two situations are difficult
Simultaneously in the same relationship
What you want to do is before assuming that this person is not at ease
Let's assume that this person is ignorant
This is a good rule of thumb for peacemaking
So maybe if your partner doesn’t do something
Maybe something happened here on the bottom
But you might want to assume that at first
They actually don't know how to do it
Then you need to break it down
Maybe you want when you go home
Get a certain form of greeting
Because you might go home from outside every day
This may be a five-minute or ten-minute interaction
So one hour a week
There are 4 hours a month and 50 hours a year
Or a whole weekday
Have time for interaction when going home
As long as you make this type of interaction 50 times correct
Your relationship can be straightened out
This is really worth thinking about
Because that's it you don't have so much time, right
Plan three meals well
Five hours a day are spent on this
Plan your sleep time properly
Achieve between you and your partner on a voluntary and negotiated basis
Effective operation of repeated basic interactions
You will spend 80% of your life like this
Then it becomes a daily routine
This would be really helpful
If you don't do it consciously
Especially because our characters are fragmented
And most of the traditional characters have disappeared
No one knows who exactly should do what
For example, when cooking
No one is doing business
In addition to scolding and fighting and doing dark dishes
Or buy fast food, etc.
Instead of causing such a catastrophic failure
Or continue to hate the fight
It’s better to use consensus and negotiation
Rebuild the entire structure from the bottom up
you can do it
You can think of this as a patriarchal structure
This inference is good
I mean it has psychological meaning
Because these are what you do as a person
But it also has political, economic and sociological significance
When you are doing these things
You also hope that it is not only acceptable to society
It is done in a way that society expects
This is the decomposition
Reasons for preventing the spread of chaos
It’s not your belief system group that stopped the spread of chaos
Not so abstract
But if you do the right thing
The chances of terrible things happening to you are reduced
It is psychologically meaningful to a certain extent
Maybe you will struggle less
Maybe you become less anxious and less depressed
But it has practical meaning to a large extent
Know if your child doesn’t leave the skateboard on the stairs
You won’t break your neck so often
This is not just a psychological matter
It’s a good thing to not hurt your neck often
So this structure is not only psychologically
Stop chaos from spreading
Here is another perspective to examine the hierarchical order of narrative
That is, the structure prevents the chaos from spreading
Maybe this is the structure I use in writing
I do all these things at the same time
This is pretty cool
When i asked a student
"What are you doing when you write the paper"
This question is difficult to answer, right
This is a broad and important question
If you want to write a thesis you have to ask yourself this question first
Pay attention to all words, phrases and sentences
And the relationship between sentences in paragraphs
Relationship between paragraphs in the article
The relationship between the article and the class
And how this class relates to your life
This paper permeates your entire life
So if i am writing
So obviously in the analysis of the highest level of resolution
My fingers move on the keyboard
My eyes move back and forth on the screen
This is where the mind and the body meet
Then I tried to conceive a sentence
Try to come up with a good sentence
A sentence that can express what I want to conceive
And then try to take it apart
I tried this in many ways
I wrote this sentence and moved it to another page
Then I wrote ten different variations of this sentence
See if you can find a better variant
Then I tried to think about how stupid this sentence can be
See if I can find a crowbar to pry it open and let it fall apart
If I can't do this, I will keep the existing sentence
Then I followed the ten sentences in a paragraph
Then make sure that every sentence in this paragraph is organized properly
So by rewriting different variants
Try to use words, phrases and sentences as accurate as possible
Also make the order of sentences correct and the order of paragraphs correct
At this time I can say it is good enough
Because i have tried my best
This does not mean that it is completely correct
It just means i can't make it better
So I came to the conclusion that if I write a paragraph
Then I wrote a variant
And I can’t tell if its variant is better
It may even be worse then I'll finish it
I have reached the limit of my knowledge
It's time to continue writing
But this does not represent the paper I wrote
It has a very tight boundary
Because I wrote this paper for a reason
That’s I’m trying to write a complete manuscript
I hope to try to deal with an important problem like this
Otherwise why should I do this
I mean it becomes a bit pointless
Maybe this is part of my role as a scientist
Is part of my role as a professor
Is also part of my role as a viable citizen
It’s me as a person who dares to face the unknown
Part of such a role
You see this is why Logos is in
At the top of this hierarchy
The hierarchical order in everything else should be constructed like this
Because you have a structure and you want
What should this structure belong to
The answer should be like this
This structure should belong to
The process that generated it
Or this structure should be subordinate to
The process of generating it and maintaining it
Obviously, what else could it be?
Unless the structure is absolutely perfect
If you do
Things that can generate it and improve it
But then you become a totalitarian
Like this "Hey we have the answer"
"No you don't"
People are still suffering they are still dying
You don’t have the so-called "answer"
Maybe the answer you currently have is to show
There would be more suffering and death in the world now
But there are still many roads to explore
So it makes sense that everything can be included
I regard it as the highest criterion of moral pursuit
Then this also gives you a moral hierarchy order
This is the most important
Be cautious and honest
You should act like this
Don't sacrifice any of it because if you sacrifice
It will erode your soul
There is such a view in the New Testament
The sin of blasphemy against the Holy Spirit is the only sin that cannot be forgiven
No one understands what this means
Maybe it doesn't mean anything
But I think the following is its meaning
Because this process generates all these
If you violate this process
Then you are incurable because through it
You can improve yourself
And improve others and everything
So if you decide you don’t participate
Then it's hopeless
Because you deviated
Things that get things fixed and resolved
So this is the way to stop chaos from spreading
Part of it is structural
You know more or less how to do these things
This part is your whole set of skills
If you happen to be a writer
You can also construct a set for plumbers
In fact, they all work the same
But the external things are the same
I think this is why in the Judeo-Christian tradition
There is an assumption that people and people are essentially equal before God
That means everyone should be nested in it
Regardless of their particularity as individuals
Their highest level function is this
They do what they can to achieve this
This is extremely valuable
Perhaps the most valuable
Socio-political and economic functions
This is why people are valuable
We have this function to continuously produce improvements
To optimize the structure in which we live together
awesome
This is great
Because this gives the fundamental unity in the analysis of the highest order
At the same time, it also has the largest controllable limit of diversity space
The facts show that the more different substructures, the better
Because you can do something different from what I do
It’s good because if we all do the same thing
Becomes repetitive work
If we agree on the highest principle
Then specialize in refinement at a lower level
It’s like you have bear paws and fish to eat
This is a rare situation
Another rule of thumb is
If you are trying to solve a problem
As far as possible before you dare to climb to a higher level
Solve it from the highest possible resolution level
As you move up into a more abstract hierarchy
When trying to solve this problem
The probability of causing catastrophic errors will increase dramatically
Because the power of abstraction is extremely powerful
So you have to be very cautious
We saw it when the housing loan market collapsed
The reason for its collapse was the improper use of financial derivatives
They are like high-level abstractions of the financial world
Financial derivatives provide you with a huge amount of capital leverage
And power are accompanied by huge risks
The benefits are huge, no doubt
Because you can double your profit
But the disadvantage is the catastrophe
I have to say that a more wise and conservative spirit is
Solve this problem from the most specific level with the highest resolution
This is safer and more likely to produce practical solutions
Now you plan
Let’s simplify it again and it’s this small map
But everything else is nested inside
So when you walk happily on the road of your life
What happened is in the process of moving from A to B
You encountered something
People think they encounter objective objects
But it’s not the case
First of all the vast majority of you
Actually everyone else is not an objective object
They are terribly complicated
Even outside the social world
What you encounter is not an objective object
They look more like tools or obstacles
I'm not saying that we see objects
And then directly turn them into tools or obstacles
I mean we will see tools or obstacles
Because when you are all geared towards your goal
At this time the world transforms into three types of things for you
A stumbling block that hinders the goal
These are what you don't like
Two boosters that make it easier for you to achieve your goals
Those are what you like
Three other unrelated things
In most cases what you want is irrelevant
Because there are so many things
The unimportant things you really like
Most things are irrelevant
If you have a good plan
Some things are good
Because they will push you forward
Some things are not so good
You want to take a detour for things that are not so good
If you can do it
Unless you like to hit the south wall with one head
It's not very wise but it is also a learning experience
But I won’t let it repeat too many times
You want the world to be displayed in the form of a set of tools
And what works here is your perception system
It is conducted by dopamine
This sensory system can also be cocaine methamphetamine
Or activated by other drugs that people like
The dopaminergic system will affect what you encounter
Things that help promote you toward your goals
Give positive emotions as a response
It's important to know this
Because people tend to think they are happy
Because they achieved their goals
It’s not so true
Because once you achieve a goal
A question came right away
That's what the next goal is
This is actually a big problem
You will meet it as soon as you graduate from university
This is an example
I used to make this joke
You are like the king among undergraduates on graduation day
You lost your job the next day
May work at Starbucks
So the obvious accomplishment itself
The source of rewards is problematic
When you are finished, the whole framework is over
Then you need a new framework
This is a problem
But if you can meet
The things that push you forward are great
This is where you can get positive motivation
This is very worth thinking about
You think it can last a year
It even takes longer
Because it means
It means to some extent
The Buddhists are right about Maya
Maya means people live in illusions
They mean if you have a goal
No matter what your goal is
Will connect you to the world
You can change your connection to the world in an instant
You can do this just by changing your goals
Then you think about it, this is an illusion
Because you can change it
You don’t want to push this argument too far
Because even specific points can be changed
The fact that you are in a certain frame cannot be changed
So you have to be in a frame
Although you can choose a framework
But there is always an absolute principle
That is you must be in a frame
This is not an absolute principle that does not matter
But a very important absolute principle
Then you think about all your positive emotions
It's all from the relationship between you and the target
Then we think we need some positive emotions
This is a good thing
Positive emotions suppress anxiety, disappointment, depression and pain
It can do it technically like this
This is why a rugby player has injured his thumb
Still desperate when trying to score a touchdown
Although this kind of goal has great uncertainty
Really? You have to risk your hand injury
Have you thrown a piece of pig skin over several posts?
Well you can also be so cynic
Most of the things people do
But you can't mock a fact
That people have to do something
So you have your intention
You have your goals, you have your ambitions
This can turn the world into a potentially positive place
This is really surprising, this is cool
The higher the goal, the more positive emotions
You think "Why should I"
"Why do I bother to do noble and difficult things?"
Because it's worth doing
Otherwise the remaining option is to suffer stupidly really
Because you don’t need to build a framework to suffer
You just lie there and suffer day after day, right?
It's easy this is the default situation
If you don't have lofty ambitions
Then you will suffer misfortune
Because life is really complicated, short and limited
Full of suffering and beyond your control
You can just lie there thinking it's scary
It's useless and useless
People often say that life is meaningless
But it's not so wrong
If life is meaningless, it's easy
You can sit here and do nothing, it doesn't matter
It’s like you become a sheep with the brain lobes removed
Everything becomes irrelevant
But it is not the case
When people say that life is meaningless
They didn't mean that
What they want to express is
"My pain is so stupid and strong
"And I don't know what to do with it."
Put it this way, suffering is full of meaning
It’s just that its meaning is not what you want
So how do you get out of this situation
You have drawn a painful baseline and this line is very high
Then you say to yourself
Okay, I need to do something to live up to the suffering
It's not easy to pain the baseline is high
If you are going to achieve something
So that I didn't live in vain
Then you have to pursue things that are perfectly constructed
So that you can tell
"Despite the death of my family from the earthquake and cancer
"The disillusionment of what I ask for, the ultimate futility of life
"Even the heat death of the universe
"But it doesn't matter, it's worth it"
There is another factor that complicates the situation
So I said when you pursue your goals
There are three things you will encounter
I would say if you want to set a goal
Or you have to make a plan
Look at the next three to five years
You can only get one situation for the further future
Combinatorial explosion
That is, there are so many variables that you cannot predict
So looking forward to 20 years does not make much sense
Because how could you know what will happen in 20 years
I don’t know you can know it for three years at most
Maybe you can make a three-year itinerary
Or about five years
It's not bad considering this for a while
Then think about what your life must be like
To make it worth visiting for you
You also need to know if life is not worth living
What would you look like
If you think it's not worth living
You will become Cain
He is like you
This is what this story tells
Abel is a man of purpose and he made appropriate sacrifices
Cain is one because of his own fault
At least to some extent
And people who are not going well
Sacrificing improper default results
Is bitter and bitter
What to say with the potential
Murderous hatred
You will put it into practice
People in the world have been performing this kind of drama
This is not surprising
Because if there is nothing noble to lead you forward
Then the baseline is stupid pain
If you have a dog, you will tie it to the backyard
Put a collar on it because the collar is too tight and it keeps grinding its skin
It doesn’t even make it all around
It's terribly hot in the sun
Maybe you didn't give it enough water
It would not be a happy dog
Its basic situation is suffering
People do the same
Okay, we don’t know if you remember
You may have all seen or heard of "Pinocchio"
There is a very cool plot in "Pinocchio"
In order to make his puppet
Become a wise autonomous life
He made a wish to the stars
It’s very strange but everyone accepted this setting
Because when we accept something completely ridiculous
Can't notice the absurdity of things
A puppeteer in an animation made a wish to the stars
Then his puppet will move
However, everyone nodded and said, "This is fine."
There is nothing
This is simply unreasonable but the point is not here
This is different from what we usually understand
This is a meta-consensus, everyone can understand
And what Geppetto did is
Raise his eyes above the horizon
Beyond the boundaries of the world
Or pass-through
So as to achieve a certain strong purpose through transcendence
You can see the transcendent
It surpasses you straight into heaven and overlooks all beings
It is very close to our goal
And there is a star there
That is an eternal star shining in the dark
Geppetto reached an agreement with Transcendent there
He said to make my creation come alive
I am willing to pay any price
This is exactly what you want to set up for yourself
You have to figure out which star you want to be your guide
You must ask yourself
"If you have a chance to make your life meaningful
"What is the price you have to pay"
"what do you need"
The first thing to do is to find the question first
You have to hint yourself like this first
You will feel scared
Because you think "I will never reach it"
Then lower your eyes first
Don't expect to get a 24m super yacht in half a year
It just makes you look stupid
First of all, it won't make you happy
So it is unwise
You should be like asking someone you care about
Ask yourself this question
For example, suppose you are talking to some
Talk to your favorite 12-year-old kid
You think, "Thank God, if this kid is going well
"That's also a good thing."
Hope you do the same
The universe doesn’t care if you are doing well
Don't care if your pain can be reduced a bit
Especially when you are not imposing pain on others
If you can suffer a little bit less sin
Make slight improvements wherever you go
Then the universe may have no objection to this
I think if you keep silent about it
You could have escaped guilt
So ask yourself that question first
When you have established your goals
You have found your position
What you know is good for you
Because it helps your future development
The next thing will happen at the perceptual level
You don't need to think about it
The experimental articles on this aspect have made it very clear
For example, suppose I put the podium
As the end of my next move
Then I will be very happy when I walk over
Because the podium is there
Things are going as I wish
And suppose I want to go to that exit sign
You may not see the exit sign
But there is an obstacle
Then when I set this goal
That's an annoying obstacle
This is foreseeable
It can be predicted the moment I set my goal
In fact, your being is displayed in these frames
But the good thing is that these frameworks can be changed for you
This does not mean
You can do things like juggling with planets
But it does provide you with a range
A world in which it is unconstrained
If this framework doesn't work
You can also adjust it
Sometimes you even have to make major adjustments
Anyway that's it
You don’t have to fix yourself in a certain frame
As if it is the ideology you want to dedicate to
This is just a tentative plan
Develops with progress
In the "Future Writing Plan"
One of my suggestions is
Everyone should scrawl the plan
Because you can't make a correct plan
But a reasonable plan is much better than no plan
Then there is a reasonable plan with an in-depth process embedded in it
After this process is activated, the plan will be continuously optimized
So it’s important to start with a reasonable plan
You don’t need to worry about whether it’s correct
It doesn't matter if it is wrong
The point is that something is better than nothing
Now you have parsed the world into two parts
Part of it will make you happy as long as you see it
The other part is the stumbling block that causes negative emotions
And a whole bunch of other insignificant things
Because most things are unrelated
And all the chaos hides in it
That is, chaos hides in unrelated things
This is a very interesting phenomenon
Since chaos is actually infinite
The question is where did you put them
The answer is of course placed in a place that you overlooked
As long as it does not actively affect your process
You can ignore it
You can assume it doesn’t matter
Assuming it means nothing
Anyway, the next thing to say is the key
There is another kind of things you may encounter in this process
This is the outburst of chaos
Now suppose
You are moving from point A to point B
Something unexpected happened on the road
Some obstacles appeared
Suppose you are living with someone
Maybe you have a good impression of this person
You are not married yet
It can be seen that I haven't liked it to that level
Otherwise, you will definitely propose to the other party
A quarter of you are expecting better things
And three-quarters of you say you are getting better
This is because we are conflicted about this type of thing
Then you find someone
Or that person admits that he has always had an affair
So how should you respond emotionally?
Part of you is not very loyal to this relationship
So this part of you is a little bit excited about it
And three-quarters of you are still indulged in it so you are sad
In the argument after you
You will definitely use the latter part
Without saying
"Oh, you betrayed me. I think I'm still a little excited."
But the point is that this is a loophole
This seems to be a structure you can walk on
Such as thin ice that can slide
Now there is a hole in this structure
We don't even know how deep this hole is
But you know there is a hole there
Now you feel anxious about it
Maybe also a little excited
Because god knows what's down there
But you are at a loss for this hole
Because it may have a bad effect on you
Maybe this whole relationship is a cover
And all your romances are just a cover
Because you are so shallow
So that you can't establish a substantial relationship
Part of the reason may be that you don’t pay attention to others
It may be because you are vicious and selfish
Realize that these are quite uncomfortable
Or maybe this is the kind of person you attract
In fact, this makes sense
If you are this kind of person
So certain things you might encounter
It will pierce your heart
And in those heartbreaking moments
Will follow the entire predictive hierarchy
A logical conclusion is
You got cheated in a relationship
It shows that you are really a bad guy
Another logical conclusion is
The person with you is a bad person
Everyone is really bad
At the macro and micro level
You can't trust anyone
You can't trust women or men
You cannot believe in humans you cannot believe in yourself
Everything is a disaster nightmare
Then you will fall into chaos
Otherwise your body will react
Let’s say you think you should be promoted
This is great and you are all discussing promotion
You were summoned by your boss and walked into the office
The boss says
"We observed your performance in recent years"
"Your performance is only slightly super mediocre"
"And we are just about to scale down."
"So goodbye to you"
This is definitely not talking about promotion or salary increase
This is a pothole you fell into
The question is how do you think about it, right
How would you define it
How would you accept the chaos that just emerged
And establish an order that can be accommodated
You do not know
"Is the entire capitalist system rotten from beginning to end"
I mean in this case
This must be a convenient explanation
Is your boss a perverted bastard
Did you choose the wrong major when you entered the university?
Is it your father's fault
Because he never allowed you to do what you want to do
Or is it because you resigned yourself to the consequences?
Or because this is a sunset industry
Or is it reminding you to join another business
Do something you always wanted to do
Things you can fight for your whole life
This is why you are so painful in your current career
Because you can’t do what you really want to do
And feel pain and resentment
God knows why
These thoughts emerged together in an instant
This is annoying
Because these ideas are too many
This is the reemergence of chaos, this is the flood
It’s like returning to the beginning of the universe
This is another manifestation of mythology
You sailed all the way and finally returned to the beginning of the universe
There is only undifferentiated chaos
This is what you are facing
Maybe it makes you unbearable
Unbearable leaving you with psychological trauma
This may hurt your brain
So fast you can't bear it
But it doesn't matter you have no way to escape
How should you respond to this situation
There are some catastrophic negative emotions
You froze and this is protective
Maybe it’s because you don’t want to move at all
You want to stay in bed for a whole week
This is because of your body's reaction
It's like there are snakes all over the bedroom floor
You better stay in bed motionless
Just freeze
This situation is not very good
Because your nerves are tight at this time, your brain is highly excited
This is very exhausting
And there is no benefit
Unless those snakes can't see you
But the snake has seen you so it's useless to be still
Now you have been affected by these indiscriminate negative emotions
Anxiety fear hurt anger guilt shame sad
Disasters are overwhelming
And maybe from the other side
Hidden in this situation is
"Thank God I finally don't have to do this job anymore."
"I have had enough"
"I struggle to go to work every day"
"A part of my heart feels"
"It's a good thing for me to be fired."
"It's so fun."
And you may not want to admit it
Because it means
The time you spend on this job is wasted
You have been deceiving yourself
But there is something interesting to think of
Sometimes it is unpleasant to have to fire someone
Sometimes fire them
It is a good way out for them
But this does not mean to enjoy the dismissal process
But I have met some very unkind people
They really like firing people
I'll tell this story if I find a chance
Because it's quite interesting
And sometimes
If some people just can’t do their job
How miserable it is to work
The best thing you can do for them is to tell them
"You did a terrible job"
"And that doesn't mean"
"You will do nothing in this world."
"Maybe you should just accept reality."
"Give up and try something else"
This is terrible for people
I know people hate this kind of thing
But it’s better than doing nothing
It’s just a tortured chronic death
So look at it from the good side
Now suppose you have fallen into a hole in the thin ice of life
You encountered an anomaly that you don't understand
You want to know how this vision formed
I know it’s weird to think about it this way
Because it’s not or let’s go down
This is a metaphor
"How did this vision form?"
One way to understand it is
It is formed by mental matter
The reason for this is as follows
This is what I learned from Piaget
It is made of matter
Because the world is made of matter
And the world is also very important
This forms a kind of duality
But it also consists of spirit
Because when you encounter a vision
And walking down the rabbit hole
You enter such an underground world
It's under everything you depend on
You will also learn something
There is information there
There may be more information than you need, but it is information
What use is this information for you
You can understand this information, right
You can use this information to cheer up
This is also beneficial
So you will think you are a mind
Maybe you think you are not a spiritual body
It depends on whether you are a materialist
But at least we can say that you are a mind
The question is what is your mind made of
It obviously has a material basis
And the matter happens to be arranged in a certain order
In order of information
So when you fall into the underground world under everything
You are exposed to the hidden information
What you can do is strengthen your mind
You can make your spirit stronger
Because all you can do is
Absorb and accept new information
It’s like eating the forbidden fruit that Adam and Eve stole.
You accept it and you are more complete
This is not a metaphorical or metaphysical proposition
Nothing else
It's like the situation when children are studying
Imagine this picture
A three-year-old child only knows the low-resolution world
And the child is still a low-resolution person
They have all the necessary elements
There is no huge difference between these elements
They will only change in the future
So what will this kid do to explore
What to explore, explore the unknown
Explore the information contained in the unknown
Because you already know what you know
There is no new information
You go to understand what you don't know
There is new information
From the information
Your understanding of the world will be clearer
Your knowledge of yourself will become clearer
So in the battle with the Chaos Dragon
You have created mind and matter
This is what you did when you entered the underground world
If chaos didn't kill you
Or make you want to die
Because you do die
But anyway, part of you has to be buried underground
But this may not be a bad thing
Because if your relationship ends because of betrayal
That means something is wrong, right?
some things
Let me explain why
You might think "Hey, I'm preaching again"
I don’t know if you noticed that I don’t mind preaching
But this judgment is not fair
Because you are playing this stupid game
It's like you're loyal to someone
This is a game right
You have decided the rules of the game
Morality comes with the game
Then morality is the rule of the game
Then things collapsed into infidelity
Either you play the game wrong or the game itself is wrong
Can only be one of the two
You chose this game
And after the election, you can’t say
These rules are not what I want
"I want to be pretty"
If you choose the game, you will default to the rules behind
If you fail to follow these rules you will lose the game
You can also say that I can choose another game
I don't care how you solve the problem
You are still trapped by it
Fundamentally speaking, this is a moral issue
And may need some earth-shaking changes to correct
You are at location A and want to go to location B
And this is not feasible, you have encountered an abnormal situation
You must not be at location B now
For example, you are a medical student
You took the MCAT, an entrance test you must pass
The bottom quarter of your ranking
I do not know who you are
But you are not a pre-medical student now
Maybe you've never been right
And this is a problem friends
You don't know who you are
There is a crash here, and a conflict of motivation
Motivation and emotions start to fluctuate here
The huge amount of information also began to surge
This is where the phoenix has changed
The burning part of the Phoenix
This is a journey to the underground world
Road to hell
This may really be a journey to hell
Because you may find out why your partner betrayed you
Or why you didn’t get a promotion
It's all because you have serious problems
And you know it well
I'm not saying you don't know what you are doing
I mean a quarter of you
Focusing on bad things
This makes you fall into the underground world and you discover next
"Oh my God, I finally made it myself."
Or "I finally got retribution from the worst part of me"
"And the worst part of me needs to be cleared."
And this is not easy
Because "I have been captured by him and cannot get out."
"I have been with it for a long time."
"Maybe I can't get rid of it all my life."
It's not fun at all
You will often see this kind of people in psychotherapy
Maybe you can see them hanging out on the street
Living completely in the past disasters like walking dead
Because they have penetrated into the underground world
Finally trapped in hell, there is no way to escape
When you meet this kind of person on the street
You will avoid it
Alright you are in the underground world now
With the potential information
Too much information
It's the same as this picture shows
This is why the story of Adam and Eve is a prototype, right?
Because we are always digesting new things
Those new things plunge us into a new state of self-consciousness
Our previous paradise will be destroyed
I don’t have everything as before
Something that followed with the new destroyed it
And beat our current life to pieces
This is the journey to the underground world
Leaving the garden and heading to Chaos
So what does all this mean
Well there are many ways to explain it
This is a frame conversion
This is a walled city
There is a gap
Every siege has gaps, isn’t it
Because nothing is perfect
Defects are the source of chaos
Maybe you go out of town and fight chaos like a hero
To re-establish the framework
And this is what you should do
Maybe you released some information when you did this
Or established a relationship
This is a journey
Frame destruction chaos
Voluntarily confront the reshaping of the world
That is the state of being
I hope it is not only linear but stepwise
"You" that emerged from the recent disaster
Just add some other things to your past self
And this actually constitutes
So-called quantifiable progress, right
There is also another view against moral relativism
If you do everything before
You can have more output on this basis
We think you are getting better
This is not a bad definition
Then we have an improvement
It's like all you have to do is analyze the world
Then make yourself different
Whenever you experience one of these revolutions
Then these two things are expected to be achieved
Then that story has moral elements
That is to do it actively
Maybe don't wait for it to happen like a disaster
Brighten your eyes
It's not too late to make up for it
Don't think it matters
Maybe this is very important
This may be the key to what you should be
This may be the key to what the world should be
If part of you tells you this is important
That means that part of you is telling you
You must solve this problem right away
This is the so-called important thing
I really like to use the word "substance"
Because it has these two weird meanings right
Material from a materialist perspective
It is the material of all things that is inanimate
In another sense, matter is the material of life
And this is important
Sometimes you are going through life and important things
It is calling you
This is the hidden world trying to show itself to you
And what you should do is allow it to show itself to you
What might happen next is
Some small changes will happen to you
You don’t have to burn a phoenix egg
Then reborn from the ashes
Maybe you just need to fix some
The wrong place on you
So you only need to experience a series of continuous and small sacrifices
Instead of waiting for a bloody disaster
A disaster you can't get out of
All you have to do is focus on the important things
Your entire nervous system is born for this
You have a goal
In the meantime, something happened
And it matters
So what should you do
You should fix it
You should face it
That's why it seems to be shouting to you it is important
It's saying that there is an unclear part of the world
This part wants to appear as a completely clear existence
And it's calling you to do it all
If you ignore it, this part will pile up
As it accumulates it will become the dragon of chaos
He will be when you are not prepared
Swallow you
And this is another result
This is not a good solution
Unless you want to be its lunch
The above is a longer introduction to Noah
But it is still necessary
Otherwise we can't understand the story
This is the meaning of this story
After that we can finish this story very quickly
Although it is unlikely to be finished within today
Let's start to tell the next story in "Genesis"
It followed the story of Cain and Abel
What starts with a short story is just a fragment
I call this story "the great man on earth"
"When there are more people in the world" (Genesis 6:1)
So this happened after the story of Cain and Abel
"When the daughter was born again" (Genesis 6:1)
"The sons of God see the beauty of human women
"Just choose and marry as your wife" (Genesis 6:2)
"Jehovah says, "Man is natural
"'My spirit won't live in him forever
"'But his life can reach one hundred and twenty years'" (Gen 6:3)
"At that time there were great men on the ground
"Later the sons of God
"Women who have sex with men have children
"That is the famous person of ancient heroism" (Genesis 6:4)
People tried many times
To explain these messy sentences
But I think it reflects the classic development of hero mythology
Seems to show nostalgia for the past
What Mircea Iliad pointed out is
What is human memory like in the pre-literal age
Because there is no written record
Those retained memories will merge with each other
Imagine a culture based on fisheries
Everyone must be a good fisherman
Those who use simple tools to fish
Are very good fishermen
They know every little detail about the fish
Because if they don’t, they won’t survive
So proficient in fishing is very important for them
They may have been fishing for about 13,000 years
Have a lot of accumulated knowledge
So the question is who taught humans to fish
The answer is a fragment of individual stories in history
But people can’t remember these story fragments
So people merge them all into a hero fisherman
He showed people the example of fishing
No matter what the paradigm is
One of the examples might be to try to catch fish
Otherwise there will be nothing in the coming year
Something like this
Just like these stories of discoveries
Was merged into the heroes of the past
What you should do as a fisherman
Is an example of practicing this hero
The concept of "ancient heroic and famous person"
Or the heroes of the past
Is a fragment of this series of thoughts
There were some great men in the past
They created the mode of existence that humans should have
They are sons of god
They picked a human woman to marry as their wife
It's funny because we know
The more capable men are, the more overwhelming they are to breed offspring
So this perfectly explains the status quo
Let's talk back to the flood
This is from Mircea Iliad
He wrote the book "History of Religious Thought"
I strongly recommend everyone to read
There are three volumes in this set
Very worth reading
Excellent
I personally like this book
The following is his description of the flood myth
"Thanks to Richard Andre Hermann Uzena
"And the work of the author of James Fraser's The Golden Branch
"The flood myth has been widely known"
"It's on every continent
"Although it’s rare in Africa
"Of course there are more deserts in Africa
"It is recorded by different levels of culture"
Some of these record variants were formed by spreading
Not caused by spontaneous innovation
"It first originated in the Mesopotamia and developed in India"
"Another possibility is due to one or more floods
"Lead to the birth of these myths and legends"
"But if there is no trace of geography left
"It's hard to explain why a myth spread so widely."
Iliad wrote this long ago
I remember it was in the 80s or 70s
But after that
Indeed, a lot of evidence has been found in different fields to prove
In the memory of related human civilization
There have been catastrophic floods
For example, the Indians on the west coast of North America
I may use the wrong word here
I don't know what to say
I know a sculptor of the Kwakwajakwa tribe
He once told me a flood story
This story is basically the same as that of Noah
Except that the ark has become a lot of giant canoes
But basically the same story
If I remember correctly, they released a raven
Noah released a raven first
Then a pigeon was released when the flood subsided
So is the story of the Tower of Babel
The canoes are all gathered together
Not a huge boat but many canoes
Drove out of the flood together
Then the boats went all over the world
This is the reason why humans are all over the world
Anyway, the story was widely spread
There have indeed been floods in North America
And not very long ago
You can check the Missoula flood
Happened about 13,000 to 15,000 years ago
Kwa Kwa Kwa tribe on the west coast
Has lived for about 13,000 to 14,000 years
Oral tradition can last a very long time
You might think it won't be like this
But the traditional society will not change
This is why they have become traditional
The same story will be passed on from generation to generation
People will remember the same story
The Missoula flood was a product of glacial meltwater
This flood happened 55 times
Occurs between 15,000 and 13,000 years ago
Released about 15 times the amount of water in the Amazon
This is a huge flood
The Society of Molecular Biology and Evolution published a paper in 2008
Titled "Climate Change in Southeast Asia and Human Migration after the Ice Age"
Which mentioned multiple floods
Especially for 15,000 to 7,000 years ago
Impact in Southeast Asia
So Iliad has no geographical evidence to prove
There may be a bit of a mistake on the point that there have been catastrophic floods.
But this is not very important
Because we still look at it from a psychological perspective
"Most of the flood myths are to some extent
"It's about the laws of the universe"
"In the old world, humanity was lost and submerged under water."
"After some time, a new world was born from this chaos."
"Although the variables are huge
"But floods are often the result of human sin or the collapse of rituals and music."
"Sometimes the reason is just that the gods wish to end humanity"
"The biggest culprit is the sin of mankind and the aging of the world"
This is a very good analysis
Because it describes a parallel relationship
We mentioned before
That is, things will collapse and not only that
If you don’t pay attention you will speed up the process
So if you are in an intimate relationship
A relationship requires a lot of work to maintain
And you know when it needs maintenance
Because of you and each other
Began to create a barrier
Then it will start to have some disgust
I hope it's not contempt but a little disgust
There may be some emotional alienation
You will feel it and then you will think
It's hard to say what you think
But no matter what you will feel
You know this feeling is sprouting
Then you have a chance
To make up for the fault no matter what
Both of you need to change
Maybe one of them needs to change more
This needs to be discussed seriously
I realize something is happening
Maybe it's my reasonMaybe it's your reason
Maybe we should figure it out
Because if it’s your problem, it’s more convenient for me
But if it is my problem, I hope I can correct it
Because this way things are resolved
This is why you should listen to your partner
Because they might tell you
Where are you stupid without knowing it
If you can correct
Then you don't have to be this stupid anymore
This is actually one of the practical functions of the companion
Otherwise you really want to stay stupid like this
Do you repeat mistakes for the rest of your life?
Compared to the argument
"Why are you so stupid" and "how to solve it"
Of course this is much more convenient for you
But it’s better to face the problem and start a dialogue
Then the biggest culprit lies in the sin of mankind and the aging of the world
Sin is generally like this
Either people did something they knew was wrong
Either he didn’t do what he knew was right
Both are similar
In the Judeo-Christian tradition
The evaluation of the crime of negligence is more severe
I think there may be some misunderstandings here
Because the crime of negligence can cause substantial disaster
So here is a concept of flood
Everyone please tell me what you think
So there is a critical being that will overwhelm you
If you continue to use it yourself
It seems a little bit
This is the Lord
An example of the tendency to be harsh in the Old Testament
Modern people don’t really agree with this
We want God to be domesticated to some extent
Unfortunately this doesn't seem to work
I often think
North America's response to the hurricane in New Orleans
Because there are two ways of understanding
One is that nature is a bit convulsive
Just let New Orleans blew a hurricane and razed everything
Isn't this a disaster
Isn’t this an example of human beings vulnerable to nature?
But at the same time there can be another interpretation
Maybe this is not very fair
But it still needs to be mentioned
The Dutch built a dam to stop the sea
They are quite efficient
Because most of their cities are below sea level
But if you go to the Netherlands, you will find that the Netherlands is not a country
So the dam is quite useful
Dutch people are very organized
They'd better be like this
Because their country should have been flooded
If your city should have been flooded
Then you better be organized
They are really organized
They set up principles for the dam
They tried to simulate
The strongest hurricane that may occur in the next 10,000 years
Then make sure their dam can withstand such disasters
From what I read
Dam built by military engineers in New Orleans
Can only cope with a storm once in a hundred years
This is not very good because we will probably live for 80 years
This means there will be one of the storms
Very likely to happen in our lifetime
So this may not be the smartest plan
Especially because part of New Orleans is below sea level
Worse
Mississippi is famous for corruption
So you can speculate
There is a lot of time, money and resources that could or should
The plan was used to deal with this problem but failed at the end
So when the hurricane hits
Some people will say this is really a natural disaster
But the question is why are you so convinced that this is a natural disaster
Because if the infrastructure should be well maintained
And it is technically feasible to rebuild to a certain specification
At the same time, the cost of reconstruction is actually lower in the long run
And everyone knows it well
So when the tornado comes and razes the town
Why do you think this is a natural disaster
For me this is a self-contained example
If you think of it as a metaphor
This is a judgmental God
Using the flood to teach people morality
You may feel a little harsh
What about those flood survivors
This flood is indeed harsh
It points out what can be done beforehand
I doubt if I did these things after the robbery
Even now everyone knows what happened
You can think of this as a diagnosis
But this is not important anymore
Actually what I want to say is
How the fairy tales overlap with these things
We can tell a story
Talking that Mother Nature will bring disasters from heaven and hide tragedies
Or you can tell another story
Talking about the social structure of fallen human beings
And how humans failed on an individual level
Which leads to a problem that everyone knows to exist
This is a good example of when people do things wrong
How did the flood come
About the Old Testament and its authors
The interesting point is
They always imagine the flood will come
This shows that they are not ready yet
The rules are like this
A priori axiom
The flood rushes to you, it means you are not ready
How did you know because you were washed away by the flood
This fact itself is evidence
You might say it's unfair
But fairness is not the point
The point is whether you still want to be flooded again
Because fairness means that you better figure out why you got caught
And you better solve the problem so that this kind of thing does not happen again
Doing this is "moral"
When you think of morality as
The most correct path chosen to reach the goal
At the same time choose the best possible goal
"The simple fact is that things exist
"That is, it will survive and create when the universe gradually declines
"Things will eventually fall into decline"
"This is why things need to be recreated"
"In other words, on a micro scale, the flood
"Symbolizes what happened in the New Year's Day celebration."
"The world has ended sin and humanity has ended
"In this way, new creations may appear."
Iliad contains a lot of information in just a few words
In the Mesopotamian ceremony
They will perform at the New Year celebration
A scene where the kingdom fell into chaos
This is what you are doing when making a plan
It is actually a degradation
you can say
Our habit of making new year's plans is a degenerate ritual
I'm not saying it's bad
I mean something greater can germinate from it
Mesopotamians
Will take their king out of the city once
They will make the king kneel
Take off all his clothes that symbolize the king's status
Then use a glove to smoke him if I remember correctly
This is done by the priest
They will account for him this year
What did not qualify as the emperor
How he failed to become a qualified Marduk
That's how he should be in the world
His head is full of eyes
Spit a magical spell
He is the one who can transform chaos into order
This is what the ruler should do
So the question should be
You are the emperor should be humble
Because you are not the incarnation of god
You may have made some mistakes
Can you think of the past year
How did you fail to seize every opportunity possible
Turn chaos into order?
It's good to think about it
When you are making a new year plan
This is what I think
Although you may not realize
Can you be a better person in the next year
You can imagine the flood
Then you set your posture and get ready
This means you may delay it
This also means that even if you fail to delay it
You may also escape
This is actually Noah's story
Noah could predict the worsening of the situation
Can predict the flood
God is letting him know all this
In a story Noah was walking with God
Remember this is Adam before he had complete self-will
What God has been doing
He walks with God
We will go into details next time
But at the same time this may mean
Noah is upright, he cheered himself up
His family relationship is harmonious
This also shows that he is very sensitive
Compared to those who are completely obscured by the fog
He can see a little further into the future
He can feel something is wrong
So he prepared for it
Because he prepared for it
Even if the flood came, Noah would be calm
This is a very interesting thing
This is an uncertain event in human existence
If everyone is ready
How big a hurricane would it take to destroy New Orleans
Anyway, the Netherlands will not be easily destroyed
Unless the wind is particularly strong
You need to imagine
An unusually powerful hurricane can blow down their dam
If no one in the city or state government engages in corruption
How strong can New Orleans' disaster relief projects be
Maybe this will solve the hurricane problem
Because we clearly understand how to deal with it
We know the countermeasures
The same principle applies to our lives
Flood is coming
No doubt about this
100% will definitely happen
Some may be personal
Some may be family
Some may be about society, politics, and economy
Will these problems be disastrous for you
Or how would you control them
How do you need to prepare
The first problem encountered is
Your behavior is in order
Enough to make you feel the coming of the problem
And have you made corresponding countermeasures?
Maybe a detour
Maybe just don’t go to the place where the flood is going to happen.
In this case, the problem is simple
But you may not be so lucky
Disaster is coming
Maybe someone in your family will be seriously ill
The path through the storm is just a small path
Things won’t fall apart when walking on this trail
If that's the end, it won't be a divorce
The end will not be death
The ending will not be grief
The ending will not be a disaster
But this fault tolerance rate is so low that it is almost close to zero
Anything you do that is not perfect will increase
The possibility of making that tragedy no different from hell
And they are on the way
They will come without a doubt
Then you might think that since it is imminent
The best thing you can do is to integrate yourself
When the problem comes
Get the worst results
I will end with a story
This matter has a deep impact on me
My mother-in-law suffered from frontotemporal dementia
She started to have symptoms when she was younger
She was about 55 years old at the time
Her husband is a very outgoing person
It's delicious locally
I grew up in a small town everyone knows him
He is very attractive and has a problem with alcohol
very attractive
Is a very powerful businessman outstanding
And he is a man of true temperament
But he is not the kind of man who cares about his family
Although he paid a lot to support his family
When his wife got sick
He is really taking care of her wholeheartedly
That's a really stopping scene
Caring for people with Alzheimer's disease
No matter what intent or purpose it is, it is not a trifle
The patient is gradually being swallowed by the disease and it is unbearable
And it's hard
It is not only catastrophic but also difficult
Oh my god but he handled it perfectly
This thing could have been worse
This is a tragedy but it did not deteriorate into hell
I was there when she died
I later found out that my wife’s family is really good at dealing with death
A sister of my wife is a hospice nurse
You need to be very strong to be a hospice nurse
But it can still be done, which is interesting
This career means that you can be in the last stage of people’s lives
Build a sincere relationship with them
Then they died in front of you one after another
But she is so competent, lively, smart and interesting
This is really amazing
She is someone who can be relied upon in a tragedy
My wife’s other sister is a pharmacist
My wife has also been a volunteer in the hospice ward
She is also good at taking care of
People with serious health problems
So we were all present when my mother-in-law died
You can imagine
You can imagine a scene before a sickbed
Your mother-in-law is dying, everyone is at a loss
If you think it’s not common, then you’re unworldly
This is simply too common
That situation is not tragedy but hell
You may be able to tolerate tragedy
But you can't tolerate hell
But it was not like that at the moment my mother-in-law died
Everyone is pulled closer
She passed away
But the result is very interesting
This family is closer
On the one hand, although something has been taken away
But on the other hand, what did you get
This is no small thing
I'm not trying to be optimistic
Not the kind of "the world is so beautiful" chicken soup
It’s very difficult for someone to die well
But my God, but things could have gotten worse
Maybe this is good enough
That's it
I am often curious
If people do their best to tell the truth
Keep an eye on your surroundings
So the tragedy of life
There is no need to deteriorate into intolerable hell
Hell does not have to be part of life
Then maybe we can tolerate tragedy
Maybe even overcome it
Or even alleviate it because we can do it
We have been doing similar things
This is an open question
Iliad described this very well
Is the flood really the result of things collapsing?
Or the flood is actually the result of people making mistakes
And these mistakes were made knowingly
Are they guilty?
This means not hitting the bullseye
Missing the bull's eye this is an archery term
Say people don't have a clear goal
You can't hit the target without aiming
Or after aiming and saying
"It's not that unimportant anyway."
Be careful when you are saying this
If you say that
One thing that might happen to you is
You may end up in hell for a long time
May even be left in hell
Some people are indeed in this situation
I have seen someone there
How to come out once you get there is no small problem
So the important thing is that important things will be handled
It’s important to walk with God as best you can
We'll talk more about it next time
This may be how you build the ark
To withstand the flood, even if the flood comes, you can retreat
The problem is that the flood will come eventually
The funny thing is that I noticed
Our education system how we teach students
For example, "trigger warning" is garbage
If it's in my class
I guess I will be warned every 15 seconds
I will tell my students when they are young
Don't fool yourself or you will get seriously ill
At least one or two or three
One is likely to be chronic
If it is not you who is sick, it will be the one you love
Will be your husband
Will be your parents
Will be your child
It will come with death and pain
When this happens
What do you want to be
This is the question that should be asked
The question should not be "how to be happy"
If so, then good luck
I think that is a stupid goal
Because it's too shallow
If you are lucky, happiness will come and walk like a cloud and see the sun
If you have achieved happiness, like you
Enjoy it
Happiness is a gift from the universe
But as a pursuit, forget it
The pursuit should be when the flood comes
You want to be the one who built the ark
This is the story of Noah
The flood will always come
This story is worth mentioning
There are apocalyptic elements in the Judeo-Christian tradition
The end of the world is always here
You should be prepared for trial
On this point, this is true
The reason is that the end of the world is imminent
Will come and you will be judged
Because when the world collapses
It's you who decide how to do it
This will be the ultimate moral issue
It will push you to the limit
You will clearly see where your unknown weakness is
Because this is what happened in a crisis
The reason why this is a realistic prototype
The coming end of the world
The reason is hidden in the entire Judeo-Christian structure
Because we have been living in the end
No matter the micro or macro in your world
Are coming to an end
What should you do to prepare
Prepare for the end of your world
When the world ends
You might get a new world
That would be a good result
Now we are finally ready for next week